Randy Herasme

randyherasme6@gmail.com | 646-573-3385 | github.com/randyher | linkedin.com/in/randy-herasme | randyherasme.com

Full stack developer with previous experience as an educator. Passion for coding stemmed from its delivery of challenge and encouragement of creativity. Skilled in Javascript, React, and Ruby on Rails. Experienced as an educator, demonstrating a team-first, problem-solving mentality, strong interpersonal skills, and the ability to internalize and implement feedback.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

No Hesitation Math GitHub: Frontend Backend | Video | Demo

Practice math facts, identify your growth areas and track your progress

- · Designed an experience that would impact mathematical growth in an entertaining way for students.
- · Integrated authentication for user sign-up and log-in with JWT so users may record and track their progress.
- · Built the user interface with React, and utilized Bootstrap and Semantic UI for styling.
- · Utilized Rails and ActiveRecord to persist user data.

Stock Purchase Github: Frontend Backend | Video | Demo

Simulate the purchase of stocks, dynamically track their performance and audit purchases

- · Developed a stock purchase application that allows you to create an account using JWT, buy stocks for their current value and track their performance through an API.
- · Built the user interface with React, and utilized Semantic for styling.
- · Utilized Rails and ActiveRecord to persist user data.

NHM for Mobile GitHub: Frontend Backend | Video

Practice and track growth on a mobile device

- · Redesigned my No Hesitation Math application on React Native for students to practice on more accessible devices.
- · Utilized Rails and ActiveRecord to persist user data, and flexbox for styling.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient in JavaScript, Node.js, Express, React, React Native, Redux, Ruby, Rails, HTML, CSS ActiveRecord and SQL

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

WeWork x Flatiron School – Brooklyn, NY

June 2019 - Present

Software Engineering Coach

- · Delivered lectures on Javascript, React, and Ruby on Rails, demonstrating and instilling proficiency in those languages and frameworks.
- · Assisted students in debugging and building applications with Javascript, React, and Ruby on Rails.
- · Managed the day-to-day schedule of students, influencing their growth and professional development.

Success Academy Charter Schools - Bronx, NY

February 2016 - August 2018

Lead Teacher

- · Effectively taught academic, behavior and social skills to elementary school students
- · Drove academic outcomes by analyzing data, studying scholar work, and implementing high leverage instructional moves to ensure dramatic gains for 32 per academic year, consistently surpassing network benchmarks.
- · Committed to closing the achievement gap and raising the bar for all children by serving primarily underprivileged children and creating a multiculturally aware and accepting classroom.

EDUCATION

Flatiron Schools Brooklyn – Brooklyn, NY

October 2018 - February 2019

Full Stack Web Development, 15 Week Immersive Program

University at Albany – Albany, NY

September 2011- May 2015

Bachelor of Arts, Major in Criminal Justice, Major in English, GPA: 3.41

ADDITIONAL

· Proficient in Spanish